{"Topic": "Rivers of the World", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "The River Seine is situated in", "op1": "Egypt", "op2": "France", "op3": "Poland", "op4": "None of these", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "New York city is situated on the bank of which of the following rivers?", "op1": "Danube", "op2": "St. Lawrence", "op3": "Hudson", "op4": "Hamburg", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following pairs is correct?", "op1": "Tigris : Baghdad", "op2": "Tiber : Paris", "op3": "Seine : Rome", "op4": "Danube : Bonn", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "From origin to the delta, the Brahmaputra traverses", "op1": "Tibet, China and Myanmar (Burma)", "op2": "Bhutan, Nepal and India", "op3": "China, India and Bangladesh", "op4": "India, Bangladesh and Myanmar (Burma)", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What name does Brahmaputra take as it discharges into the Bay of Bengal?", "op1": "Ganga", "op2": "Jamuna", "op3": "Padma", "op4": "Meghna", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The famous American river Mississippi flows into the Gulf known as", "op1": "The Gulf of Mexico", "op2": "The Gulf of St. Lawrence", "op3": "The Gulf of Ob", "op4": "None of these", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which one of the following cities is located on the bank of the Irrawady river?", "op1": "Bangkok", "op2": "Hanoi", "op3": "Manila", "op4": "Yangon", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Paris is situated on the river", "op1": "Danube", "op2": "Seine", "op3": "Tiber", "op4": "Avon", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which one among the following rivers is the longest?", "op1": "Amazon", "op2": "Amur", "op3": "Congo", "op4": "Lena", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Match List 1 with List 2 and select the correct answer using the code given below the Lists :", "op1": "A - 3; B - 2; C - 4; D - 1", "op2": "A - 4; B - 1; C - 3; D - 2", "op3": "A - 3; B - 1; C - 4; D - 2", "op4": "A - 4; B - 2; C - 3; D - 1", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "e :", "op1": "Indus", "op2": "Ganga", "op3": "Sutlej", "op4": "Brahmaputra", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one of the following Indian rivers does not have its source in Tibet?", "op1": "5890 km", "op2": "6690 km", "op3": "7320 km", "op4": "4950 km", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What is the length of the Nile (appx), which is the longest in the world?", "op1": "Colorado", "op2": "Mississippi", "op3": "Hudson", "op4": "Mackenzie"}, {"Question": "On the banks of which are the capital cities of Austria, Serbia and Hungary located?", "op1": "Seine", "op2": "Volga", "op3": "Euphrates", "op4": "Danube", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "On which of the following rivers is the Aswan Dam located?", "op1": "Irrawady", "op2": "Hwang Ho", "op3": "Nile", "op4": "Congo", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following rivers has no bridges over it?", "op1": "Nile", "op2": "Hwang Ho", "op3": "Amazon", "op4": "Volga", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Mesopotamian civilization thrived in the area between which two rivers?", "op1": "Euphrates and Nile", "op2": "Tigris and Euphrates", "op3": "Nile and Tigris", "op4": "Euphrates and Diyala", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Into which of the following water bodies does the River Nile empty itself?", "op1": "Gulf of Oman", "op2": "Red Sea", "op3": "Mediterranean Sea", "op4": "Gulf of Aden", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which country does not have any river flowing through it?", "op1": "Saudi Arabia", "op2": "Iran", "op3": "Turkey", "op4": "Iraq", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the deepest river in the world?", "op1": "Amazon", "op2": "Nile", "op3": "Congo", "op4": "Volga", "Answer": 1}]}